As the name suggests,
顾名思义
discretization is basically converting a continuous space into a discrete one.
离散化就是将连续空间转换为离散空间
Remember our continuous vacuum cleaner world?
还记得连续吸尘器环境吗？
All we're saying is let's bring back a grid structure with discrete positions identified.
我们重新回到标识了离散位置的网格结构
Note that we're not really forcing our agent to
注意 我们并非强迫智能体
be in exactly the center of these positions.
必须位于这些位置的中心区域
Since the underlying world is continuous,
因为底层环境是连续的
we don't have control over that.
因此我们无法控制这一状况
But in our representation of the state space,
但是在我们的状态空间表示法中
we only identify certain positions as relevant.
我们仅关心某些位置标识信息
For instance, whether the robot is at 3.1, 2.4,
例如 无论机器人位于 (3.1, 2.4) 还是 (2.9,1.8)
or 2.9, 1.8, we can round that off to three, two.
我们都可以四舍五入为 (3,2)
Yes, this will almost always be a little incorrect,
没错 这么处理肯定会不太准确
but for some environments,
但是对于某些环境
discretizing the state-space can work out very well.
离散化状态空间效果很好
It enables us to use existing algorithms with little, or no modification.
使我们能够几乎不加修改就能使用现有的算法
Actions can be discretized as well.
动作也可以离散化
For example, angles can be divided into whole degrees,
例如 角可以拆分为完整度数
or even 90 degrees increments, if appropriate.
甚至按 90 度递增 如果合适的话
Now, let's imagine there are objects in this discretized world,
现在假设这个离散化环境中有一些物体
obstacles that the robot may need to avoid.
机器人需要绕过这些障碍物
With our grid representation,
对于网格表示法
all we can do is mark off the cells where an object is present, even by a little.
我们只能标记存在物体的单元格 甚至稍微超出范围
This is known as an occupancy grid.
称之为占据网格
But our choice of discretization may lead the agent into thinking,
但是我们的离散化方式可能会使智能体以为
there is no path across these obstacles to reach some desired locations.
没有绕过这些障碍物以抵达目标位置的道路
Instead, if we could vary the grid according to these obstacles,
如果我们能够根据这些障碍物调整网格
then we could open up a feasible path for the agent.
那么可以为智能体找到一条潜在的道路
An alternate approach would be to divide up the grid into smaller cells where required.
另一种方法是在需要时将网格拆分为更小的单元格
It would still be an approximation.
依然是逼近结果
But it'll allow us to allocate more of our state representation to where it matters.
但是可以让我们在需要的位置分配更多的状态表示
Better than dividing the entire state space into finer cells,
这样比将整个状态空间拆分为更小的单元格合适
which may increase the total number of states,
拆分整个状态空间可能会增加状态的总数
and in turn, the time needed to compute value functions.
进而增加计算值函数所需的时间
If you're familiar with binary space partitioning,
如果你熟悉二叉空间分割或四元树的话 理解起来就很简单
or quad trees, this is exactly the same idea.
其实这是完全相同的概念
Now, you may be wondering.
现在你可能会疑问
This sort of discretization makes sense in spacial domains like gridworlds.
这种离散化适合网格世界等空间领域
But what about other state spaces?
但是其他状态空间呢？
Let's change gears and look at a different domain.
我们来看看汽车换挡这个不同领域的问题
Most cars these days have automatic transmission.
如今的大部分汽车都会自动换挡
Have you ever wondered how the car decides to pick what gear to switch to, and when?
你可曾想过 汽车如何决定切换到哪一挡以及何时换挡
Here's a simplified plot of how fuel consumption
这个图表简单地描述了对于一辆普通汽车
varies with speed for different gears in a typical car.
油耗如何随着不同挡位速度的变化而变化
Let's assume that our state only consists of the vehicle speed,
假设状态仅包含车辆速度
and which gear we are in.
以及当前挡位
And our reward is inversely proportional to fuel consumption.
奖励与油耗成反比
The actions available to our agent are essentially switching up, or down.
智能体可以采取的动作包括换到更高挡位或更低挡位
Now, although speed is a continuous value,
虽然速度是连续值
it can be discretized into ranges,
但是可以离散化为不同的范围
such that a single gear is the most optimal in each range.
最佳划分方式是一个挡位对应一个速度范围
Note that these ranges can be of different lengths,
注意这些范围可以具有不同的长度
that is, the discretization is non-uniform.
即离散化是不均匀的
If there were other dimensions to the state-space such as throttle position,
如果状态空间还有其他维度 例如油门位置
then they could be subdivided non-uniformly as well.
那么它们也可以不均匀地细分